[
  {
    "id": 1901,
    "question": "esposo",
    "questionDetails": "Conocí a mi esposo en julio de 1972.",
    "answer": "husband",
    "answerDetails": "I met my husband in July of 1972."
  },
  {
    "id": 1902,
    "question": "dólares",
    "questionDetails": "Enviamos millones de dólares.",
    "answer": "dollars, bucks, USD",
    "answerDetails": "We sent millions of dollars."
  },
  {
    "id": 1903,
    "question": "preocupada",
    "questionDetails": "Parece preocupada y cansada.",
    "answer": "worried, concerned, preoccupied",
    "answerDetails": "She looks worried and tired."
  },
  {
    "id": 1904,
    "question": "ex",
    "questionDetails": "Ella y su exmarido siguen siendo buenos amigos.",
    "answer": "former",
    "answerDetails": "She remains good friends with her former husband."
  },
  {
    "id": 1905,
    "question": "termine",
    "answer": "Finish"
  },
  {
    "id": 1906,
    "question": "pudiste",
    "questionDetails": "¿Pudiste haber dejado tu bolsa en la fiesta?",
    "answer": "could you",
    "answerDetails": "Could you have left your purse at the party?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1907,
    "question": "tengamos",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie de que tengamos que preocuparnos.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "Nobody you have to worry about."
  },
  {
    "id": 1908,
    "question": "firmar",
    "questionDetails": "Así usted y su experto pueden firmar estos.",
    "answer": "sign",
    "answerDetails": "So you and your expert can sign these."
  },
  {
    "id": 1909,
    "question": "clave",
    "questionDetails": "Necesito la clave para el crucigrama del New York Times.",
    "answer": "key, password",
    "answerDetails": "I need the key to the New York Times crossword puzzle."
  },
  {
    "id": 1910,
    "question": "respecto",
    "questionDetails": "En este respecto, creo que cada país tiene que asumir la responsabilidad por un futuro sostenible.",
    "answer": "regard, with respect to",
    "answerDetails": "In that regard, I think each country must assume responsibility for a sustainable future."
  },
  {
    "id": 1911,
    "question": "chiste",
    "questionDetails": "Steven contó muchos chistes en la fiesta para hacernos reír.",
    "answer": "joke, prank",
    "answerDetails": "Steven told a lot of jokes at the party to make us laugh."
  },
  {
    "id": 1912,
    "question": "bolsa",
    "questionDetails": "Llegar temprano a la bolsa de un asiento en la primera fila.",
    "answer": "bag, stock exchange, pouch",
    "answerDetails": "Get there early to bag a seat in the front row."
  },
  {
    "id": 1913,
    "question": "mensajes",
    "questionDetails": "No hay más mensajes claros en este mundo.",
    "answer": "messages, posts, emails",
    "answerDetails": "There are no more clear messages in this world."
  },
  {
    "id": 1914,
    "question": "podrá",
    "questionDetails": "Así tendrás un cuerpo del que nadie podrá decir nada.",
    "answer": "can",
    "answerDetails": "Get a body that no one can say anything about."
  },
  {
    "id": 1915,
    "question": "consigo",
    "questionDetails": "Marina se llevó a los niños consigo.",
    "answer": "with her",
    "answerDetails": "Marina took the kids with her."
  },
  {
    "id": 1916,
    "question": "salieron",
    "answer": "Left"
  },
  {
    "id": 1917,
    "question": "sobra",
    "questionDetails": "La sobra de maíz hizo que bajara el precio del cereal.",
    "answer": "surplus",
    "answerDetails": "The surplus of corn brought the price of cereal down."
  },
  {
    "id": 1918,
    "question": "pasas",
    "questionDetails": "Ahora es tiempo de agregar las pasas.",
    "answer": "raisins, spend, currants",
    "answerDetails": "Now it’s time to add the raisins."
  },
  {
    "id": 1919,
    "question": "igualmente",
    "questionDetails": "La discusión de seguimiento es igualmente importante.",
    "answer": "equally, similarly, likewise",
    "answerDetails": "Follow-up discussion is equally as important."
  },
  {
    "id": 1920,
    "question": "decidir",
    "questionDetails": "Decidir hacer algo.",
    "answer": "decide",
    "answerDetails": "To decide to do something."
  },
  {
    "id": 1921,
    "question": "quedarte",
    "questionDetails": "De veras no tienes que quedarte.",
    "answer": "stay, stick around",
    "answerDetails": "You really don’t have to stay."
  },
  {
    "id": 1922,
    "question": "sonrisa",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Deja de mirarme con esa sonrisa tonta y contesta a la pregunta!.",
    "answer": "grin",
    "answerDetails": "Quit looking at me with that foolish grin and answer the question!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1923,
    "question": "caras",
    "questionDetails": "Las dos caras y las cabezas están perfectamente enfocadas.",
    "answer": "faces, expensive, sides",
    "answerDetails": "Both the faces and headlines are in perfect focus."
  },
  {
    "id": 1924,
    "question": "sabíamos",
    "questionDetails": "Ni siquiera nosotros sabíamos.",
    "answer": "knew",
    "answerDetails": "None of us knew."
  },
  {
    "id": 1925,
    "question": "buscamos",
    "questionDetails": "Buscamos en el sótano pero no encontramos nada.",
    "answer": "we looked",
    "answerDetails": "We looked in the basement but we didn’t find anything."
  },
  {
    "id": 1926,
    "question": "decían",
    "questionDetails": "Como decían cuando interrumpiste, la tienda ya cerró.",
    "answer": "they were saying, they would say",
    "answerDetails": "As they were saying when you interrupted, the store has already closed."
  },
  {
    "id": 1927,
    "question": "mmm",
    "questionDetails": "Mmm deberías tener algo.",
    "answer": "mmm, um, hmm",
    "answerDetails": "Mmm you should have some."
  },
  {
    "id": 1928,
    "question": "casar",
    "questionDetails": "Y te vuelves a casar una semana después del divorcio.",
    "answer": "marry, get married",
    "answerDetails": "And you get to marry one weeks after divorce."
  },
  {
    "id": 1929,
    "question": "amistad",
    "questionDetails": "La amistad y el amor son lo más importante en la vida.",
    "answer": "friendship, friendliness",
    "answerDetails": "Friendship and love are the most important things in life."
  },
  {
    "id": 1930,
    "question": "talento",
    "questionDetails": "Me refiero a nuestro verdadero, aunque único, talento.",
    "answer": "talent",
    "answerDetails": "I mean our real, if only, talent."
  },
  {
    "id": 1931,
    "question": "decirles",
    "questionDetails": "Mis padres vendrán mañana. No puedo esperar a decirles de mi trabajo nuevo.",
    "answer": "tell them",
    "answerDetails": "My parents are coming over tomorrow. I can’t wait to tell them about my new job."
  },
  {
    "id": 1932,
    "question": "firme",
    "questionDetails": "Durante el terremoto, la torre se mantuvo firme.",
    "answer": "steady, steadfast, solid",
    "answerDetails": "The tower remained steady during the earthquake."
  },
  {
    "id": 1933,
    "question": "mintiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Ellos están mintiendo contra las doctrinas.",
    "answer": "lying, Iying, lyin’",
    "answerDetails": "They are lying against the doctrines."
  },
  {
    "id": 1934,
    "question": "vernos",
    "questionDetails": "Pero podríamos no volver a vernos por un buen rato.",
    "answer": "seeing each other, meet, hang out",
    "answerDetails": "But we might not be seeing each other for a while."
  },
  {
    "id": 1935,
    "question": "delito",
    "questionDetails": "Cometer un delito, delinquir.",
    "answer": "crime, offence, offense",
    "answerDetails": "To commit a crime."
  },
  {
    "id": 1936,
    "question": "quítate",
    "questionDetails": "Quítate la ropa ahora mismo.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "Take all your clothes off right now."
  },
  {
    "id": 1937,
    "question": "sacaste",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que ya me sacaste todo el veneno.",
    "answer": "got",
    "answerDetails": "I think you got all the venom out."
  },
  {
    "id": 1938,
    "question": "metí",
    "questionDetails": "Me metí justo en el medio del lío.",
    "answer": "got, shoved",
    "answerDetails": "I got right on top of that mess."
  },
  {
    "id": 1939,
    "question": "estaré",
    "questionDetails": "Yo estaré muy honrado.",
    "answer": "be",
    "answerDetails": "I would be very honoured."
  },
  {
    "id": 1940,
    "question": "muevas",
    "questionDetails": "Necesito que no muevas tu cuello.",
    "answer": "move",
    "answerDetails": "I need you to not move your neck."
  },
  {
    "id": 1941,
    "question": "ilusión",
    "questionDetails": "¿Fue magia de veras o simplemente una ilusión?",
    "answer": "illusion",
    "answerDetails": "Was that really magic or just an illusion?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1942,
    "question": "pega",
    "questionDetails": "Siempre habrá pegas; se trata de cómo lidies con ellas.",
    "answer": "snag",
    "answerDetails": "There will always be snags; it’s just about how you deal with them."
  },
  {
    "id": 1943,
    "question": "famoso",
    "questionDetails": "El país es famoso por su belleza natural.",
    "answer": "famous, renowned",
    "answerDetails": "The country is famous for its natural beauty."
  },
  {
    "id": 1944,
    "question": "recuerdos",
    "questionDetails": "Colecciona portadas de álbumes, fotos y otros recuerdos de los Beatles.",
    "answer": "memorabilia, associations",
    "answerDetails": "She collects Beatles album covers, photos, and other memorabilia."
  },
  {
    "id": 1945,
    "question": "libres",
    "questionDetails": "Los chicos tienen que ser libres en la escuela.",
    "answer": "free",
    "answerDetails": "Children must be free at school."
  },
  {
    "id": 1946,
    "question": "robo",
    "questionDetails": "Brandon fue detenido por robo de autos.",
    "answer": "theft, robbery, steal",
    "answerDetails": "Brandon was arrested for auto theft."
  },
  {
    "id": 1947,
    "question": "parezca",
    "questionDetails": "Y eso hace que parezca como si fuera verdad.",
    "answer": "seem, look, oddly enough",
    "answerDetails": "And that makes it seem as if it were true."
  },
  {
    "id": 1948,
    "question": "haberlo",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie podía haberlo planeado.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "Nobody could have planned this."
  },
  {
    "id": 1949,
    "question": "tirado",
    "questionDetails": "Si encuentro tus juguetes tirados en el suelo, ¡ los boto a la basura!.",
    "answer": "lying",
    "answerDetails": "If I find your toys lying on the floor, I’ll put them in the trash!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1950,
    "question": "levanta",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando levanta la mano a la cabeza.",
    "answer": "raises, rises, lift",
    "answerDetails": "When it raises hand at the top."
  },
  {
    "id": 1951,
    "question": "mires",
    "questionDetails": "A menos que mires por aquí.",
    "answer": "look, stare at, stare",
    "answerDetails": "Except if you look over here."
  },
  {
    "id": 1952,
    "question": "vuelven",
    "questionDetails": "Estas cosas vuelven y vuelven.",
    "answer": "return, come back",
    "answerDetails": "These things do return."
  },
  {
    "id": 1953,
    "question": "lunes",
    "questionDetails": "Te llamaré el lunes.",
    "answer": "monday",
    "answerDetails": "I’ll ring you Monday."
  },
  {
    "id": 1954,
    "question": "cuente",
    "questionDetails": "Haz que el sacrificio cuente para algo.",
    "answer": "count",
    "answerDetails": "Make the sacrifice count for something."
  },
  {
    "id": 1955,
    "question": "belleza",
    "questionDetails": "Es una verdadera Belleza.",
    "answer": "beauty",
    "answerDetails": "She really is a beauty."
  },
  {
    "id": 1956,
    "question": "ambulancia",
    "questionDetails": "Puedo llamar un taxi o una ambulancia.",
    "answer": "ambulance",
    "answerDetails": "I could call you a cab or an ambulance."
  },
  {
    "id": 1957,
    "question": "norte",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes ver si estás caminado hacia el norte usando el sol y un reloj.",
    "answer": "north",
    "answerDetails": "You can see if you’re walking to the north by using the sun and a watch."
  },
  {
    "id": 1958,
    "question": "pusiste",
    "questionDetails": "Pusiste salvia en los sandwich es?",
    "answer": "put",
    "answerDetails": "Put sage in the sandwiches?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1959,
    "question": "volar",
    "questionDetails": "Guy Fawkes urdió un complot para volar el Parlamento británico el 5 de noviembre de 1605.",
    "answer": "blast",
    "answerDetails": "Guy Fawkes plotted to blast the Houses of Parliament on November 5th, 1605."
  },
  {
    "id": 1960,
    "question": "interés",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que está perdiendo interés en mí.",
    "answer": "interest",
    "answerDetails": "I think he’s losing interest in me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1961,
    "question": "fría",
    "questionDetails": "La sopa está fría.",
    "answer": "cold, cool, chilly",
    "answerDetails": "The soup is cold."
  },
  {
    "id": 1962,
    "question": "golpes",
    "questionDetails": "El equipo de rescate escuchaba golpes de dentro del edificio derrumbado.",
    "answer": "knocking",
    "answerDetails": "Rescuers could hear a knocking coming from the collapsed building."
  },
  {
    "id": 1963,
    "question": "enfermedad",
    "questionDetails": "La violencia es una enfermedad social y debe ser tratada como tal.",
    "answer": "disease, illness, sickness",
    "answerDetails": "Violence is a social disease and it should be treated as such."
  },
  {
    "id": 1964,
    "question": "propósito",
    "questionDetails": "El propósito de Kim es de ser la mejor gimnasta en su estado.",
    "answer": "aim, purpose",
    "answerDetails": "Kim’s aim is to be the best gymnast in her state."
  },
  {
    "id": 1965,
    "question": "ponerme",
    "questionDetails": "No tengo nada lindo para ponerme.",
    "answer": "wear, get",
    "answerDetails": "I have nothing nice to wear."
  },
  {
    "id": 1966,
    "question": "llegas",
    "questionDetails": "Pero una vez que llegas a ello.",
    "answer": "arrive, get",
    "answerDetails": "But once you arrive to it."
  },
  {
    "id": 1967,
    "question": "tendremos",
    "questionDetails": "Si regresas mañana, tendremos un nuevo cargamento de este zapato.",
    "answer": "we will have, we will get",
    "answerDetails": "If you come back tomorrow, we will have a new shipment of this shoe."
  },
  {
    "id": 1968,
    "question": "quedando",
    "questionDetails": "Mi familia se está quedando en casa.",
    "answer": "staying",
    "answerDetails": "My family’s staying at my place."
  },
  {
    "id": 1969,
    "question": "emoción",
    "questionDetails": "Su voz estaba llena de emoción mientras recordaba la vida de su abuela.",
    "answer": "emotion, thrill",
    "answerDetails": "Her voice was full of emotion as she remembered her grandmother’s life."
  },
  {
    "id": 1970,
    "question": "mandado",
    "questionDetails": "¿Tienes que hacer algún mandado?-Sí, tengo que ir al correo, al banco y a la farmacia.",
    "answer": "errand",
    "answerDetails": "Do you have any errands to do?-Yes, I need to go to the post office, the bank, and the pharmacy."
  },
  {
    "id": 1971,
    "question": "enseñó",
    "questionDetails": "Estoy agradecido con Jim. Me enseñó una valiosa lección.",
    "answer": "he taught, he showed",
    "answerDetails": "I am grateful to Jim. He taught me a valuable lesson."
  },
  {
    "id": 1972,
    "question": "escuchas",
    "questionDetails": "Tú lo escuchas, pero no te giras.",
    "answer": "hear, listen, listeners",
    "answerDetails": "You hear him, but you don’t turn around."
  },
  {
    "id": 1973,
    "question": "podíamos",
    "answer": "could"
  },
  {
    "id": 1974,
    "question": "reír",
    "questionDetails": "Sus chistes siempre me hacen reír.",
    "answer": "laugh",
    "answerDetails": "His jokes always make me laugh."
  },
  {
    "id": 1975,
    "question": "cola",
    "questionDetails": "Tu perro mueve la cola porque está contento.",
    "answer": "tail",
    "answerDetails": "Your dog wags his tail because he’s happy."
  },
  {
    "id": 1976,
    "question": "empiezo",
    "questionDetails": "El empiezo de esa canción me da risa.",
    "answer": "beginning",
    "answerDetails": "The beginning of that song makes me laugh."
  },
  {
    "id": 1977,
    "question": "formar",
    "answer": "make up"
  },
  {
    "id": 1978,
    "question": "salía",
    "questionDetails": "Había una mano que salía de la computadora.",
    "answer": "out",
    "answerDetails": "There was a hand coming out of the computer."
  },
  {
    "id": 1979,
    "question": "carro",
    "questionDetails": "Enganchó los caballos al carro.",
    "answer": "cart, carriage, wheels",
    "answerDetails": "He hitched the horses up to the cart."
  },
  {
    "id": 1980,
    "question": "droga",
    "questionDetails": "Drogarse, tomar drogas.",
    "answer": "drug, dope",
    "answerDetails": "To take drugs."
  },
  {
    "id": 1981,
    "question": "nena",
    "questionDetails": "¿Nena, estás bien? Te ves triste.",
    "answer": "baby",
    "answerDetails": "Are you okay, baby? You look sad."
  },
  {
    "id": 1982,
    "question": "averiguar",
    "questionDetails": "Debo averiguar esto para mi investigación.",
    "answer": "ascertain",
    "answerDetails": "I must ascertain this for my investigation."
  },
  {
    "id": 1983,
    "question": "piense",
    "questionDetails": "Piense en qué diría si estuviera viva.",
    "answer": "think, consider",
    "answerDetails": "Think what she would say if she were alive."
  },
  {
    "id": 1984,
    "question": "llamadas",
    "questionDetails": "Que hagan sus propias llamadas.",
    "answer": "calls, phone calls",
    "answerDetails": "Have them make their own calls."
  },
  {
    "id": 1985,
    "question": "medios",
    "questionDetails": "Cada país en el mundo tiene los medios para hacer etanol.",
    "answer": "means",
    "answerDetails": "Every country in the world has the means to make ethanol."
  },
  {
    "id": 1986,
    "question": "documentos",
    "questionDetails": "El cumplimiento de los documentos contables.",
    "answer": "documents, papers, records",
    "answerDetails": "The completion of accounting documents."
  },
  {
    "id": 1987,
    "question": "revisar",
    "questionDetails": "El médico me ha aumentado la dosis y va a revisar la situación dentro de 6 meses.",
    "answer": "review, check, revise",
    "answerDetails": "The doctor increased my dose and is going to review the situation in 6 months’ time."
  },
  {
    "id": 1988,
    "question": "estrella",
    "questionDetails": "Su destino de golf fue escrito en las estrellas.",
    "answer": "star",
    "answerDetails": "His golf destiny was written in the stars."
  },
  {
    "id": 1989,
    "question": "invitar",
    "questionDetails": "Le tuve que invitar.",
    "answer": "invite",
    "answerDetails": "I had to invite him."
  },
  {
    "id": 1990,
    "question": "hazlo",
    "questionDetails": "Me da miedo echarme un clavado a la piscina.-¡ Hazlo ya!.",
    "answer": "do it",
    "answerDetails": "I’m afraid to dive into the pool.-Do it already!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1991,
    "question": "espectacular",
    "questionDetails": "El capitán de la Selección Inglesa anotó un gol espectacular en los momentos finales del partido.",
    "answer": "spectacular, dramatic",
    "answerDetails": "The England captain scored a spectacular goal in the final moments of the game."
  },
  {
    "id": 1992,
    "question": "venta",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Rompimos el récord hoy con 150 ventas en total!.",
    "answer": "sale, selling",
    "answerDetails": "We broke the record today at 150 total sales!."
  },
  {
    "id": 1993,
    "question": "sur",
    "questionDetails": "Dakota del Sur.",
    "answer": "south",
    "answerDetails": "South Dakota."
  },
  {
    "id": 1994,
    "question": "material",
    "questionDetails": "¿Han traído todo el material para hacer el trabajo?",
    "answer": "equipment",
    "answerDetails": "Have you brought all the equipment to do the job?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1995,
    "question": "preparando",
    "questionDetails": "Me pasé semanas preparando esa expedición.",
    "answer": "preparing, getting ready, prepping",
    "answerDetails": "I spent weeks preparing that expedition."
  },
  {
    "id": 1996,
    "question": "vivido",
    "answer": "vivid"
  },
  {
    "id": 1997,
    "question": "funcionar",
    "questionDetails": "Funcionarios contratados que trabajan con las deudas de sus padres.",
    "answer": "work",
    "answerDetails": "Indentured servants working off their parents’ debts."
  },
  {
    "id": 1998,
    "question": "dulce",
    "questionDetails": "Compré unos dulces para los niños.",
    "answer": "sweet, fresh, sugar",
    "answerDetails": "I bought some sweets for the kids."
  },
  {
    "id": 1999,
    "question": "distancia",
    "questionDetails": "Educación a distancia.",
    "answer": "distance",
    "answerDetails": "Distance learning."
  },
  {
    "id": 2000,
    "question": "veinte",
    "questionDetails": "Estuvieron aquí hace menos de veinte minutos.",
    "answer": "twenty",
    "answerDetails": "They were here less than twenty minutes ago."
  }
]